<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="G19581110">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Letter #8a from Robert Graves to William Graves <date when="1958-11-10">Nov 10th 1958</date>
                </title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Digital Humanities at Oxford Summer School</publisher>
                <pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
                <date when="2015-07">July 2015</date>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Letters from Robert and Beryl Graves to William Graves 1957-1967. 41 ALS and TLS,
                    56pp. , St John’s College (Oxford) Library, Special Collections (Holmes 4) , Box
                    4 Gp17 </p>
                <p>ST JOHN'S COLLEGE LIBRARY COLLECTION OWNED LETTERS FROM ROBERT (1895-1985) &amp;
                    BERYL (1915-2003) GRAVES TO WILLIAM GRAVES (1940- ) </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sending">
                    <persName ref="#GravesRobert">Robert Graves</persName>
                    <settlement ref="#Deia">Deya</settlement>
                    <date when="1958-11-10">Nov 10th 1958</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="receiving">
                    <persName ref="#GravesWilliam">William Graves</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <p>-<placeName ref="#Deia">Deya</placeName>, <date>Nov 10th 1958</date>-
            <lb/>Dear <persName ref="#GravesWilliam">William</persName>, <persName ref="#ReidAlastair">Alastair</persName>'s address at his next port of call is: Don
            <lb/>Quixote del Mar, C/O Commander Nicholson, English Harbour, Antigua, British 
            <lb/>West Indies[*]. I don't know how long it will take him to get to <placeName ref="#NewYork">New York</placeName> 
            <lb/>but you can get him in New York   C/O Jess McNab, 86 Horatio Street, N.Y.C.14</p>
            <p>With any luck you should get your sobrasada soon as the Pickstones 
            <lb/>know someone who is driving back to <placeName ref="#England">England</placeName> this week and I have given them 
            <lb/>one to give him. If he takes it he will leave it with the Bevans's - people 
            <lb/>we used to know in <placeName ref="#Barcelona">Barcelona</placeName> and met again soon after you left for <placeName ref="#London">London</placeName>. 
            <lb/>He, Bernard Bevan is mentioned in the great mushroom book, and in 
            <lb/>fact he was one of the first people to go to the Mexican tribe which 
            <lb/>Wasson later wrote about. The joke was he didn't know that he was in the 
            <lb/>book until he called on us at the very moment when we had that book on the 
            <lb/>table and were showing it to <persName ref="#ReidAlastair">Alastair</persName>'s friend Alastair. Their address 
            <lb/>is: 35, Elm Park Gardens, S.W.10. FLAX 4256. and this man who is taking the 
            <lb/>sobrasada lives opposite them and will leave it with them - that is of 
            <lb/>course, if the Pickstones find him to give it to him! I have put your 
            <lb/>address on the packet so the <persName ref="#AneurinBevan">Bevan</persName>'s will probably get in touch with you if 
            <lb/>etc.</p>
            <p>Will see Pedro about the gloves today, and will post them as soon as. 
            <lb/>Also the guitar things.</p>
            <p>Juan has started his O level this month. <persName>Selby</persName> has left the school, 
            <lb/>in fact he was asked not to return, and poor <persName>Abdullah</persName> has been expelled 
            <lb/>as he found it impossible to conform to school rules and also give up 
            <lb/>smoking[**]. By the way, did you ever get a pipe?</p>
            <p>No more news, and I'm getting cold sitting here, typing!</p>
            <p>Love from us all,</p>
            <p>
                <signatures>Mother</signatures>
            </p>
            <p>Margins:  Sorry to say I've just worked through your letters and can find 
            <lb/>no mention of what you wanted for your guitar. Did I dream it or was it on 
            <lb/>an envelope. Send a p.c. saying what &amp; I'll airmail it.</p>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>