<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="teibp.xsl"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Title</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>ST JOHN'S COLLEGE LIBRARY COLLECTION OWNED LETTERS FROM ROBERT (1895-1985) AND BERYL
               (1915- ) GRAVES TO WILLIAM GRAVES (1940- )</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <correspDesc>
                <correspAction type="sending">
                    <persName ref="#GravesRobert">Robert Graves</persName>
                    <settlement ref="#Canellun"><placeName>Canellun, Deià</placeName></settlement>
                    <date when="1960-08-11">1960-08-11</date>
                </correspAction>
                <correspAction type="receiving">
                    <persName ref="#GravesWilliam">William Graves</persName>
                </correspAction>
            </correspDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <pb facs="WG.60.08.11.a.jpg"/>
            <opener>
                <placeName ref="#Canellun">Canellun, Deya, Mallorca, Spain</placeName>
                <salute>Dearest <persName ref="#GravesWilliam">
                        <choice>
                            <abbr>Wm</abbr>
                            <expan>William</expan>
                        </choice>
                    </persName>,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Thanks very much for the longest letter by at least five pages you have ever written
            home; I hate the thought of the alternative methods of death you have to choose on those
            glaciers, but I know you have a bias in favour of life.</p>
            <p> I hope you got money I sent you Poste Restante at <placeName>Linthal</placeName>.
               <orgName ref="#LombardOdier">Lombard Odier</orgName> are prepared to send you up to £100
            in Swiss francs whenever you call on them. In case you have lost their address at
               <placeName>Corraterie 11, Geneva</placeName>.</p>
            <p>
                <placeName ref="#Deya">Deya</placeName> is more hectic than ever. We have only <persName ref="#GravesJuan">Juan</persName> &amp; 
                <persName ref="#GravesTomas">Tomás</persName>
            here, <persName ref="#Debbie">Debbie</persName> is with the Foggs at <persName>Emmi</persName>'s house(x),
            Lucia is away in <placeName ref="#Palma">Palma</placeName> meeting the right sort of boy friend. </p>
            <p>Our frigidaire came. We pulled down most of the larder to stick it in; where the broom
            cupboard used to be. It went like a charm for two days but has seized up owing to
            carbonized wicks from the stinking petroleo we get here. Just charring off the wick
            evenly in the hope we can get it alight again. </p>
            <p>Hot weather. Old Gardener. <persName>The Reeves</persName> all arrived, but no <persName>Antonia</persName> of the 
            <placeName ref="Puigpunent">Puig</placeName> to look after them and no substitute. <persName>Caroleena</persName> had
            an exploratory operation to see if she had cancer - fortunately not -<persName>Mary Reid</persName> borrowed
            her house (being expelled from the Posada by the <persName>Reeves</persName>) &amp; gave a 1st birthday party
            for <persName>Jasper</persName>. Everyone was there including two marvellous Israeli singers. In the middle
            of the feast there was a sharp angry explosion from the table where I wasn't: <persName>Frank</persName>
            insulting <persName>Esteban</persName> who wanted to kill him in consequence. Fortunately the <rs>Señora de
            Canellun</rs> quickly tugged at <persName>Esteban</persName>'s sleeve and changed places with him, so parted the
            two. A quarrel about Abstract Painting &amp; about that dim gipsy pansy <persName>Viola</persName> who was at
            the party and who gives me &amp; <persName ref="#GravesBeryl">Beryl</persName> and <persName>Esteban</persName> the creeps, but to others is tops. </p>
            <p><persName ref="LomaxAlan">Alan Lomax</persName> came of course the day after you left, with <persName>Shirley Collins</persName> who sings at the
            <placeName>Troubadour</placeName> and remembers you; it was terrific; &amp; <persName>Po</persName> &amp; <persName>Pedro</persName> sang <persName>Sa Ximbomba</persName>. We
            also heard a tape of the play; unfortunately part of the record got super-impressed on
            another part; but a lot survived including half of your superb talking blues &amp;
            <persName>Lucia</persName>'s song about the Wetbacks and the Rio and Cropton House and all the bangs. The
            night you left, <persName>Margot</persName> said she wanted to get out of <placeName>Can Quet</placeName>, so we asked <persName>Ricardo</persName> to
            lend her <placeName>Sa Guarda</placeName>, which he did. Apparently he had also lent it to <persName>Kitty</persName>, who arrives
            tonight. Fortunately <persName>Margot</persName> &amp; <persName>Kitty</persName> are close friends, so there'll be no lio </p>
            <p><persName>Tom Sanders</persName> got a sudden phosphorous flame from a match &amp;amp; thought he had won
            25,000 pesetas; but alas it was only a 25 peseta prize (red <pb facs="WG.60.08.11.b.jpg"/>flame instead of green). <persName>Alastair</persName> and I really think that
            the <title>White Goddess</title> film is coming off. We saw the Mati film which had some terrific
            moments; <persName>Brad</persName> was remarkable as a cad-comedian; <persName>Kate</persName> enchanting, and <persName>Margot</persName> even better
            when photographed than in three dimensions. <persName ref="#GravesBeryl">Beryl</persName> says she ought to star as the <title>White
            Goddess</title>; but that will be hard to force on <persName ref="#MorrisWilliam">William Morris</persName>, who may want some ghastly
            <persName ref="LorenSofia">Sofia Loren</persName> or someone. The melons are ripe and yellow and taste like heaven. The sea is
            calm. We have no more water troubles. Tomorrow I shall go into <placeName>Palma</placeName> &amp; get the
            address you need.</p>
            <closer>
                <salute>Love from</salute>
                <signed><persName>Father</persName> &amp; all</signed>
            </closer>
            <note place="margin">Can Cabello, Deya; or C/o us.</note>
            <note resp="#GravesBeryl" rendition="#red">Forgets you were there! love <persName ref="#GravesBeryl">Mother</persName>
            </note>
            <note>William spent six weeks in the Alps doing geological field mapping as part of the
            geology course. The Play (an annual event on RG's birthday) that year was “Lawrence and
            the Wetbacks”. William had sung a “talking blues” in it. Mati's film had a weak story
            line but shows various of the Deya characters at the time including, RG, Margot, Bill
            Waldren.</note>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>